<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="wlr_foreign_toplevel_management_unstable_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2018 Ilia Bozhinov

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="zwlr_foreign_toplevel_manager_v1" version="3">
    <description summary="list and control opened apps">
      The purpose of this protocol is to enable the creation of taskbars
      and docks by providing them with a list of opened applications and
      letting them request certain actions on them, like maximizing, etc.

      After a client binds the zwlr_foreign_toplevel_manager_v1, each opened
      toplevel window will be sent via the toplevel event
    </description>

    <event name="toplevel">
      <description summary="a toplevel has been created">
        This event is emitted whenever a new toplevel window is created. It
        is emitted for all toplevels, regardless of the app that has created
        them.

        All initial details of the toplevel(title, app_id, states, etc.) will
        be sent immediately after this event with the corresponding events in
        zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1.
      </description>
      <arg name="toplevel" type="new_id" interface="zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1"/>
    </event>

    <request name="stop">
      <description summary="stop sending events">
        Indicates the client no longer wishes to receive events for new toplevels.
        However the compositor may emit further toplevel_created events, until
        the finished event is emitted.

        The client must not send any more requests after this one.
      </description>
    </request>

    <event name="finished">
      <description summary="the compositor has finished with the toplevel manager">
        This event indicates that the compositor is done sending events to the
        zwlr_foreign_toplevel_manager_v1. The server will destroy the object
        immediately after sending this request, so it will become invalid and
        the client should free any resources associated with it.
      </description>
    </event>
  </interface>

  <interface name="zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1" version="3">
    <description summary="an opened toplevel">
      A zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1 object represents an opened toplevel
      window. Each app may have multiple opened toplevels.

      Each toplevel has a list of outputs it is visible on, conveyed to the
      client with the output_enter and output_leave events.
    </description>

    <event name="title">
      <description summary="title change">
        This event is emitted whenever the title of the toplevel changes.
      </description>
      <arg name="title" type="string"/>
    </event>

    <event name="app_id">
      <description summary="app-id change">
        This event is emitted whenever the app-id of the toplevel changes.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string"/>
    </event>

    <event name="output_enter">
      <description summary="toplevel entered an output">
        This event is emitted whenever the toplevel becomes visible on
        the given output. A toplevel may be visible on multiple outputs.
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output"/>
    </event>

    <event name="output_leave">
      <description summary="toplevel left an output">
        This event is emitted whenever the toplevel stops being visible on
        the given output. It is guaranteed that an output_enter event for
        this output was emitted before this event.
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output"/>
    </event>

    <request name="maximize">
      <description summary="request that the toplevel be maximized">
        Requests that the toplevel be maximized. If the maximized state actually
        changes, this will be indicated by the state event.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="unset_maximize">
      <description summary="request that the toplevel be unmaximized">
        Requests that the toplevel be unmaximized. If the maximized state actually
        changes, this will be indicated by the state event.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="minimize">
      <description summary="request that the toplevel be minimized">
        Requests that the toplevel be minimized. If the minimized state actually
        changes, this will be indicated by the state event.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="unset_minimize">
      <description summary="request that the toplevel be unminimized">
        Requests that the toplevel be unminimized. If the minimized state actually
        changes, this will be indicated by the state event.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="activate">
      <description summary="request that the toplevel be activated">
        Request that this toplevel be activated on the given seat.
        There is no guarantee the toplevel will be actually activated.
      </description>
      <arg name="seat" type="object" interface="wl_seat"/>
    </request>

    <request name="close">
      <description summary="request that the toplevel be closed">
        Send a request to the toplevel to close itself. The compositor may
        currently not be able to close the toplevel at the time the request
        is received. In that case, the request will be ignored.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="set_rectangle">
      <description summary="the rectangle which represents the toplevel">
        The rectangle of the surface that is representing the toplevel. This
        rectangle is in the "surface local coordinates" of the layer surface
        interface. It allows the compositor to define a placement for the
        toplevel (e.g. for the minimize animation).
      </description>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface"/>
      <arg name="x" type="int"/>
      <arg name="y" type="int"/>
      <arg name="width" type="int"/>
      <arg name="height" type="int"/>
    </request>

    <event name="state">
      <description summary="the toplevel state changed">
        This event is emitted immediately after the zlw_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1
        is created and each time the toplevel state changes, either because of a
        compositor action or because of a request in this protocol.
      </description>
      <arg name="state" type="array"/>
    </event>

    <event name="done">
      <description summary="all information about the toplevel has been sent">
        This event is sent after all changes in the toplevel state have been
        sent.

        This allows changes to the toplevel properties to be seen as
        atomic, even if they happen via multiple events.
      </description>
    </event>

    <event name="closed">
      <description summary="this toplevel has been destroyed">
        This event means the toplevel has been destroyed. It is guaranteed there
        won't be any more events for this zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1. The
        toplevel itself becomes inert so any requests will be ignored. After the
        client receives this event, it should destroy this object.
      </description>
    </event>

    <enum name="state">
      <description summary="types of states on the toplevel">
        The different states that a toplevel can have. These have the same meaning
        as the states with the same names defined in xdg-toplevel
      </description>
      <entry name="maximized" value="0"/>
      <entry name="minimized" value="1"/>
      <entry name="activated" value="2"/>
      <entry name="fullscreen" value="3"/>
    </enum>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor" since="1">
      <description summary="destroy the zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1 object">
        Destroys the zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1 object.

        This request should be called either when the client does not want to
        use the toplevel object any more or after the closed event to avoid
        leaking the object.
      </description>
    </request>

    <event name="parent" since="2">
      <description summary="parent change">
        This event is emitted whenever the parent of the toplevel changes.

        No event is emitted when the parent of this toplevel is null.
      </description>
      <arg name="parent" type="object" interface="zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1" allow-null="true"/>
    </event>

    <request name="set_fullscreen" since="2">
      <description summary="request that the toplevel be fullscreened">
        Requests that the toplevel be fullscreened on the given output. If the
        fullscreen state actually changes, this will be indicated by the state
        event.
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output" allow-null="true"/>
    </request>

    <request name="unset_fullscreen" since="2">
      <description summary="request that the toplevel be unfullscreened">
        Requests that the toplevel be unfullscreened. If the fullscreen state
        actually changes, this will be indicated by the state event.
      </description>
    </request>
  </interface>
</protocol>
